Guide to the Roland Herbert Bainton Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Writings / Talks, Series III
  - Monographs
    - Bernardino Ochino - partial ms. (Box 12, Folder 196)
    - Bernardino Ochino - letters (Box 12, Folder 197)
    - Church of Our Fathers - excerpts for teaching purposes, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 198)
    - The Panorama of the Christian Church in Kodachrome Slides, 1944,1945 (Box 12, Folder 199,200)
    - The Panorama of the Christian Church - set of slides with descriptions, 1944,1945 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - The Martin Luther Christmas Book - sources, list of letters received re. book, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 201)
    - The Martin Luther Christmas Book - drafts, notes (Box 12, Folder 202)
    - Here I Stand - complimentary copy list, partial drafts, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 203)
    - Here I Stand - corrections (Box 12, Folder 204)
    - Hunted Heretic - foreword, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 205)
    - The Covenant in the Wilderness, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 206)
    - Friends in Relation to the Churches - The Ward Lecture, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 206)
    - Roland Bainton Speaks on the Martin Luther Motion Picture, ca.1955 (Box 13, Folder 206)
    - Vignettes of Men Memorialized in the Buildings of the Yale Divinity School, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 207)
    - Yale and the Ministry - chapters eliminated, list of letters received re. book, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 208)
      Related Materials
      An original edition of Yale and the Ministry, signed by the author is in Box OV1
    - Yale and the Ministry - partial drafts (Box 13, Folder 209)
    - Pilgrim Parson - complimentary copy list, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 210)
    - The Douglas Clyde Macintosh Fellowship in Theology and the Philosopy of Religion, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 211)
    - Christian Attitudes toward War and Peace - partial drafts, corrections, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 212)
    - Early and Medieval Christianity: Collected Papers - draft for foreword, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 213)
      A signed copy of Early and Medieval Christianity is in Box OV1
    - The Horizon History of Christianity - partial drafts, revisions, notes, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 214)
    - Erasmus of Christendom - letters, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 215)
    - Erasmus of Christendom - partial drafts, notes (Box 13, Folder 216, 217)
    - Women of the Reformation - chapter drafts, by individual (B-Ci), 1971,1973,1977 (Box 13, Folder 218)
    - Women of the Reformation - (Co - L) (Box 13, Folder 219)
    - Women of the Reformation - Isabel de la Cruz (Box 13, Folder 220)
    - Women of the Reformation - (Ma) (Box 13, Folder 221)
    - Women of the Reformation - (Mo) (Box 14, Folder 222)
    - Women of the Reformation - (N) (Box 14, Folder 223)
    - Women of the Reformation - (P - R) (Box 14, Folder 224)
    - Women of the Reformation - (S - Z) (Box 14, Folder 225)
    - Behold the Christ - letters, notes, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 226)
    - Yesterday, Today, and What Next? - notes, partial draft, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 227)
    - Roly: Chronicle of a Stubborn Nonconformist (autobiography) - notes, letters, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 228)
    - Roly: Chronicle of a Stubborn Nonconformist (autobiography) - original draft (Box 14, Folder 229-232)
    - Roly: Chronicle of a Stubborn Nonconformist (autobiography) - partial draft, illustrations (Box 15, Folder 233)
    - Roly: Chronicle of a Stubborn Nonconformist (autobiography) - draft (Box 15, Folder 234)
    - Roly: Chronicle of a Stubborn Nonconformist (autobiography) - partial drafts, notes (Box 15, Folder 235)
    - Roly: Chronicle of a Stubborn Nonconformist (autobiography) - proof sheets incl. illustrations (Box 16, Folder 236-238)
  - Translations
    - Castellio's Reply to Beza ( Nonum Prematur In Annum ), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 239)
    - A Czech hymn, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 240)
  - Articles Published in Monographs
    See "Bibliography of Works By and About Roland H. Bainton" by Cynthia W. Lund (box 11, folder 83) for listing of titles of articles by RHB
    - Studies in church history, 1922-1931 (Box 17, Folder 241)
    - Studies in church history, 1938-1950 (Box 17, Folder 242)
    - Studies in church history, 1951 (Box 17, Folder 243)
    - Studies in church history, 1953-1955 (Box 17, Folder 244)
    - Studies in church history, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 245)
    - Studies in church history, 1957-1958 (Box 17, Folder 246)
    - Studies in church history, 1960-1963 (Box 17, Folder 247)
    - Studies in church history, 1965-1967 (Box 17, Folder 248)
    - Studies in church history, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 249)
    - Studies in church history, 1970-1974 (Box 17, Folder 250)
    - Studies in church history, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 251)
    - Studies in church history, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 252)
    - Studies in church history, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 253)
    - Studies in church history, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 254)
    - Studies in church history, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 255)
    - re. teaching and writing, 1946-1975 (Box 18, Folder 256)
    - re. issues of war and peace, 1948-1966 (Box 18, Folder 257)
    - re. concerns of the pastoral ministry, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 258)
    - re. popular faith and preaching, 1959-1968 (Box 18, Folder 259)
    - re. the Church and society, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 260)
  - Articles Published in Periodicals
    - Studies in Church History, 1923-1925 (Box 18, Folder 261)
    - Studies in Church History, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 262)
    - Studies in Church History, 1931 (Box 18, Folder 263)
    - Studies in Church History, 1932 (Box 19, Folder 264)
    - Studies in Church History, 1936 (Box 19, Folder 265)
    - Studies in Church History, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 266)
    - Studies in Church History, 1940 (Box 19, Folder 267)
    - Studies in Church History, 1941 (Box 19, Folder 268)
    - Studies in Church History, 1941 (Box 19, Folder 269)
    - Studies in Church History, 1941/42 (Box 19, Folder 270)
    - Studies in Church History, 1943 (Box 19, Folder 271)
    - Studies in Church History, 1943 (Box 19, Folder 272)
    - Studies in Church History, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 273)
    - Studies in Church History, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 274)
    - Studies in Church History, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 275)
    - Studies in Church History, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 276)
    - Studies in Church History, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 277)
    - Studies in Church History, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 278)
    - Studies in Church History, 1953-1954 (Box 19, Folder 279)
    - Studies in Church History, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 280)
    - Studies in Church History, 1955-1956 (Box 20, Folder 281)
    - Studies in Church History, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 282)
    - Studies in Church History, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 283)
    - Studies in Church History, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 284)
    - Studies in Church History, 1960-1967 (Box 20, Folder 285)
    - Studies in Church History, 1968-1971 (Box 20, Folder 286)
    - Studies in Church History, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 287)
    - Studies in Church History, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 288)
    - re. teaching and writing, 1932-1962 (Box 20, Folder 289)
    - re. issues of war and peace, 1938-1943 (Box 20, Folder 290)
    - re. issues of war and peace, 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 291)
    - re. issues of war and peace, 1949-1958 (Box 20, Folder 292)
    - re. issues of war and peace, 1960-1971 (Box 20, Folder 293)
    - re. issues of war and peace, 1972-1982 (Box 21, Folder 294)
    - re. concerns of the pastoral ministry, 1918-1952/53 (Box 21, Folder 295)
    - re. concerns of the pastoral ministry, 1953-1958 (Box 21, Folder 296)
    - re. popular faith and preaching, 1938-1953 (Box 21, Folder 297)
    - re. popular faith and preaching, 1959-1983 (Box 21, Folder 298)
    - re. the Church and society, 1940-1949 (Box 21, Folder 299)
    - re. the Church and society, 1954-1966 (Box 21, Folder 300)
    - re. Quakers, 1947-1974 (Box 21, Folder 301)
    - re. Yale, 1955-1971 (Box 21, Folder 302)
    - Miscellaneous, 1944-1978 (Box 21, Folder 303)
    - "Luther, Begin and the Jews", in Christianity and Crisis, 41:15 (1981), and related material (Box 21, Folder 304,305)
    - "Luther and the Jews: An Exchange; The Prime Minister and the Professor", in Christianity and Crisis, 42:4 (1982), and drafts (Box 21, Folder 306)
  - Articles Published in Encyclopedias and Dictionaries
    - Miscellaneous, 1934-1970 (Box 21, Folder 307)
    - "Reformation" and other articles in Encyclopedia Brittanica, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 307a)
    - "Martin Luther" in The Encyclopedia Americana, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 308)
    - "Protestantism" in Instituto di Scienze e Arti encyclopedia, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 308)
    - "Martin Luther", "Reformation" in Catholic Peoples Encyclopedia, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 309)
    - "Reformation", in Brittanica Junior Encyclopedia, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 310)
    - Typescript drafts of articles for encyclopedia published by Garzanti, on Calvin, Erasmus, Luther, Ohino, Servetus, ca. 1973 (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Book Reviews by Bainton
    Arranged by last name of author.
    - A (Box 22, Folder 311)
    - Ba - Bl (Box 22, Folder 312)
    - Bo - Bu (Box 22, Folder 313)
    - C (Box 22, Folder 314)
    - D (Box 22, Folder 315)
    - E (Box 22, Folder 316)
    - F (Box 22, Folder 317)
    - G (Box 22, Folder 318)
    - H (Box 22, Folder 319)
    - I (Box 22, Folder 320)
    - J (Box 22, Folder 321)
    - K (Box 22, Folder 322)
    - L (Box 22, Folder 323)
    - M (Box 22, Folder 324)
    - N (Box 23, Folder 325)
    - O (Box 23, Folder 326)
    - P (Box 23, Folder 327)
    - R (Box 23, Folder 328)
    - S (Box 23, Folder 329)
    - T (Box 23, Folder 330)
    - V (Box 23, Folder 331)
    - W (Box 23, Folder 332)
    - Z (Box 23, Folder 333)
    - Reviews of multiple authors (Box 23, Folder 334-336)
    - Author unknown (Box 23, Folder 337)
  - Introductions and Forewords
    - Intro. to Inquisitio De Fide ed. by Craig R. Thompson, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 338)
    - Intro. to book on humanism and Reformation (Box 23, Folder 339)
    - Intro. to "Three Papers on the Role of Women in the Reformation", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 340)
    - Poetry (Box 23, Folder 341)
    - Words for Music (Box 23, Folder 342)
  - Reviews of Bainton's books
    - Behold the Christ (Box 24, Folder 343)
    - Bibliography of the Continental Reformation (Box 24, Folder 344)
    - Christian Attitudes toward War and Peace (Box 24, Folder 345)
    - The Church of our Fathers (Box 24, Folder 346)
    - Collected Papers (Box 24, Folder 347)
    - Concerning Heretics (Box 24, Folder 348)
    - David Joris (Box 24, Folder 349)
    - Erasmus of Christendom (Box 24, Folder 350-353)
    - George Lincoln Burr: His Life (Box 24, Folder 354)
    - Here I Stand (Box 24, Folder 355-357)
    - The Horizon History of Christianity (Box 25, Folder 358)
    - Hunted Heretic (Box 25, Folder 359)
    - The Martin Luther Christmas Book (Box 25, Folder 360)
    - The Medieval Church (Box 25, Folder 361)
    - Pilgrim Parson (Box 25, Folder 362)
    - The Reformation of the Sixteenth Century (Box 25, Folder 363)
    - The Travail of Religious Liberty (Box 25, Folder 364)
    - Ulrich von Hutten and the German Reformation (translation by RHB) (Box 25, Folder 365)
    - Women of the Reformation (Box 25, Folder 366)
    - Yale and the Ministry (Box 25, Folder 367)
    - Yesterday, Today, and What Next? (Box 25, Folder 368)
    - Reviews of RHB articles (Box 25, Folder 369)
    - General reviews of RHB's work (Box 25, Folder 370)
  - Unpublished writings
    - "Authority and Religious Knowledge" (Theol. Discussion Group), 1935 (Box 26, Folder 371)
    - "The Bible and Western Culture", 1967 (Box 26, Folder 372)
    - "Calvin and the Liberal Reformers" (Box 26, Folder 373,374)
    - "A Christ to the Neighbor", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 375)
    - "Christianity", no date (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - "Christianity and War", no date (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - "Christmas Behind Barbed Wire" (Box 26, Folder 375)
    - "Comments on Wilhelm Pauck's paper on The Idea of the Church in Christian History" (Theol. Discussion Group), 1936 (Box 26, Folder 375)
    - "The De-Formation of Christianity", no date (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - "Erasmus and Italy", 1967 (Box 26, Folder 376)
    - "Eschatology: I. Types and Times of Christian Eschatology" (Theol. Discussion Group), 1941 (Box 26, Folder 376)
    - "The Ethic of Peace and War in Recent Pronouncements of Catholic Leaders", 1968 (Box 26, Folder 376)
    - "Hebrews 11", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 377)
    - "Holy Smoke", 1981 (Box 26, Folder 377)
    - "Humor, Pathos and Sublimity in Religion", no date (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - "Les Huguenots", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 377)
    - "La Biblia y la Reforma", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 378)
    - "The League of Nations in the Middle Ages", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 378)
    - "Letters from Roland Bainton nos.1-9"; from Germany, distributed by American Friends Service Committee, 1948 Jun-Sep (Box 26, Folder 379)
    - "Luther on Marriage", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 380)
    - "The Office of the Minister's Wife in New England" (Dudlian Lecture) (Box 26, Folder 381)
    - "Nature, Grace, Sacraments: III. Grace and Nature in Christianity from the beginning through the Reformation" (Theol. Disc. Group), 1939 (Box 26, Folder 382)
    - "Not Peace But Only Withdrawal" - letter to editor of New Haven Register re. Vietnam, ca. 1969 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - "Piety and Art" (Box 26, Folder 383)
    - "Poland Resurgent" (Box 26, Folder 384)
    - "The Principate of Augustus" (Honors thesis, Whitman College), 1914 (Box 26, Folder 384)
    - Re. portraits in YDS Refectory: Henry Ward Beecher, Eleazar Fitch, Josiah Willard Gibbs, Frank Chamberlin Porter, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 385)
    - "The Protestant Work Ethic According to Beza and Calvin" (Box 27, Folder 386)
    - "Protestantism and the Integration of Life" (Box 27, Folder 387)
    - "Public Transportation to Parochial Schools", n.d. (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - "Religion and the Rise of Capitalism" (co-authored with Liston Pope) (Box 27, Folder 388)
    - "The Religion of the Renaissance", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 389-391)
    - "Religious Liberty and Religious Knowledge: A Commentary on a Sixteenth Century Manuscript of Sebastian Castellio" (Box 27, Folder 392)
    - "The Return of the Puritan", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 393)
    - "The Roman Peace and the Christian Peace" (Box 27, Folder 394)
    - "Russian-Berlin Conversations" (summary of a conference RHB attended in Berlin of a small group of German Christians; distributed by the American Friends Service Committee), 1948 Aug (Box 27, Folder 395)
    - "Saint Peter in Storage" (re. Dura Europus), n.d. (Box 27, Folder 396)
    - "Satire and Caricature" (Box 27, Folder 396)
    - Re. Servetus, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 396)
    - "A Trip to the Moon", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 397)
    - "Winning the Peace" (co-authored with others), n.d. (Box 27, Folder 397)
    - "Ulrich Zwingli 1484-1531", n.d. (Box 27, Folder 397)
    - Untitled (re. human rights in Poland, re. Anabaptists), ca.1976,n.d. (Box 27, Folder 398)
    - Miscellaneous partial drafts (Box 27, Folder 399-401)
    - Questionable authorship by Bainton (Box 27, Folder 402)
  - Addresses/Lectures
    - "The Aarhus Conference", 1956 (Box 28, Folder 403)
    - "Christian Adversatives", 1953 (Box 28, Folder 403)
    - "Death", 1972 (Box 28, Folder 403)
    - "The East Windsor Congregational Church and the New England Tradition", 1952 (Box 28, Folder 403)
    - on Erasmus, 1968,1979 (Box 28, Folder 404)
    - "Interdependence", 1976 Jul 4 (Box 28, Folder 405)
    - "Joint Worship; Catholic-Protestant", 1966 (Box 28, Folder 405)
    - Lectures in South America: "The Spanish and the Saxon Soul" (Box 28, Folder 406-408)
    - Re. Lutherans in Holland (Box 28, Folder 409)
    - "Life and Change", 1954 (Box 28, Folder 410)
    - "Luther and the Bible", 1982 (Box 28, Folder 410)
    - "Our Pilgrim Heritage", 1953 (Box 28, Folder 410)
    - "The Reformation" - set of four cassette audiotapes: "Martin Luther and the Reformation"; "Martin Luther's Christmas Story"; "Erasmus, Prophet of Unity"; "Women of the Reformation": lectures delivered at the Ecumenical Continuing Education Center, Yale University. (digital copies of files available) (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - "The Story of Congregationalism", n.d. (Box 28, Folder 411)
    - "Trust and Thank" (Box 28, Folder 411)
  - Other
    - Marriages, obituaries, funerals (Box 28, Folder 412)
    - Marriage services, 1952-1979 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Prayers (Box 28, Folder 413)
    - Sermons, sermon notes (Box 28, Folder 414-416)
    - Sermons, sermon notes (Box 86, Folder 4)
- Course-Related Materials, Series IV
  - Topical sequence
    - Abelard (Box 29, Folder 417)
    - Anabaptism (Box 29, Folder 418)
    - Bohemia (Box 29, Folder 419)
    - Calvin (Box 29, Folder 420)
    - Catholic (Box 29, Folder 421)
    - Charlemagne to the Crusades (Box 29, Folder 422)
    - Conciliar Period (Box 29, Folder 423)
    - Constantine through Julian (Box 29, Folder 424)
    - Early Christian Doctrines (Box 29, Folder 425)
    - Early Church (Box 29, Folder 426)
    - England (Box 29, Folder 427)
    - England in the 19th Century (Box 29, Folder 428)
    - French Wars of Religion (Box 29, Folder 429)
    - Jerome (Box 29, Folder 430)
    - Jesuits (Box 29, Folder 431)
    - John Knox (Box 29, Folder 432)
    - Methodism (Box 29, Folder 433)
    - Monasticism (Box 29, Folder 434-435)
    - Mysticism (Box 30, Folder 436)
    - Pietism (Box 30, Folder 437)
    - Puritan (Box 30, Folder 438)
    - Puritan Revolution (Box 30, Folder 439)
    - Quaker (Box 30, Folder 440)
    - Renaissance (Box 30, Folder 441)
    - St. Francis (Box 30, Folder 442)
    - Scholasticism (Box 30, Folder 443)
    - Wars of Religion (Box 30, Folder 444)
    - Wyclif (Box 30, Folder 445)
    - Zwingli (Box 30, Folder 446)
  - By course title
    - "Christian Attitudes to Social Problems" (Box 30, Folder 447)
    - "History of Christian Social Teaching" - Ambrose (Box 30, Folder 448)
    - "History of Christian Social Teaching" - Early Church (Box 30, Folder 449)
    - "History of Christian Social Teaching" - Inquisition (Box 30, Folder 450)
    - "History of Christian Social Teaching" - Jews (Box 30, Folder 451)
    - "History of Christian Social Teaching" - Medieval sects, Monasticism (Box 30, Folder 452)
    - "History of Christian Social Teaching" - Natural law (Box 30, Folder 453)
    - "History of Christian Social Teaching" - Property (Box 30, Folder 454-455)
    - "History of Christian Social Teaching" - St. Thomas (Box 30, Folder 456)
    - "History of Christian Social Teaching" - Sex (Box 31, Folder 457)
    - "History of Christian Social Teaching" -Bibliographies (Box 31, Folder 458-460)
  - Bibliographies
    - By Bainton:
      - St. Augustinus (Box 31, Folder 461,462)
      - Early and medieval periods (Box 31, Folder 463)
      - Reformation (Box 31, Folder 464)
      - Modern European church history; other (Box 31, Folder 465)
      - Of Frank Chamberlin Porter, Benjamin W. Bacon, Preserved Smith (Box 31, Folder 466)
    - Bibliographical material assembled by Bainton:
      - Anabaptist (Box 31, Folder 466a)
      - Iconography (Box 31, Folder 466b)
      - Luther (Box 31, Folder 467,468)
      - Reformation (Box 31, Folder 469-471)
      - Servetus (Box 31, Folder 471a)
      - Re. Beinecke acquisitions (Box 31, Folder 472)
      - Card files: Art, Early Church. Middle Ages (social tolerance) (Box 32, Folder 473)
      - Calvin and Calvinism, Reformation (Box 33, Folder 474)
      - Miscellaneous or fragmentary bibliographical material (Box 34, Folder 475-479)
  - Other course-related material
    - Syllabi (Box 34, Folder 480)
    - Exams (Box 34, Folder 481)
    - Handouts (Box 34, Folder 482)
    - Student seminar précis (Box 34, Folder 483)
    - Unidentified seminar précis (Box 34, Folder 484)
- Notes/Source Materials, Series V
  This series is organized alphabetically by topic. Several folders of uncategorized notes follow the topical sequence.
  - The Manual of Phonography - shorthand system used by Bainton (Box 34, Folder 485)
  - Topical sequence
    - Johann Agricola (Box 34, Folder 486)
    - Alcohol (Box 34, Folder 487-489)
    - Anabaptists (Box 35, Folder 490,491)
    - Art (Box 35, Folder 492)
    - Augustine (Box 35, Folder 493)
    - Richard Baxter (Box 35, Folder 494)
    - Christoph Brenz (Box 35, Folder 495)
    - Otto Brunfels (Box 35, Folder 495a)
    - John Calvin (Box 35, Folder 496-500)
    - Sebastian Castellio -Influence of the De Haereticis (Box 35, Folder 501)
    - Sebastian Castellio -Occasion and authors of the De Haereticis (Box 35, Folder 502)
    - Sebastian Castellio -Sebastian Franck (Box 35, Folder 503)
    - Sebastian Castellio -miscellaneous (Box 35, Folder 504,506)
    - Sebastian Castellio -miscellaneous (Box 36, Folder 507,508)
    - Sebastian Castellio - re. Reply to the Antibellius of Theodore Beza, discovered by Bruno Becker in Remonstrant Library in Rotterdam (Box 84, Folder 12)
    - Christian Attitudes toward War and Peace -Bibliographical material (Box 36, Folder 509,510)
    - Christian Attitudes toward War and Peace -Classical secondary literature, New Testament (Box 36, Folder 511)
    - Christian Attitudes toward War and Peace -Classical sources (Box 36, Folder 512)
    - Christian Attitudes toward War and Peace -Crusades (Box 36, Folder 513)
    - Christian Attitudes toward War and Peace -Early Church (Box 36, Folder 514-516)
    - Christian Attitudes toward War and Peace -Modern (Box 36, Folder 517-520)
    - Christian Attitudes toward War and Peace -Old Testament (Box 37, Folder 521)
    - Christian Attitudes toward War and Peace -Pax et Bellum (Box 37, Folder 522-525)
    - Christian Attitudes toward War and Peace -Renaissance (Box 37, Folder 526)
    - Christian Attitudes toward War and Peace -U.S. churches on war (Box 37, Folder 527)
    - Christian Attitudes toward War and Peace -U.S.: New England, colonial (Box 37, Folder 528)
    - Christian Attitudes toward War and Peace -Wars of religion; Quakers (Box 37, Folder 529)
    - Christian Attitudes toward War and Peace -miscellaneous (Box 37, Folder 530,531)
    - Christian social teaching (Box 37, Folder 532)
    - Christian theology (Box 37, Folder 533,534)
    - Christmas (Box 38, Folder 535)
    - Congregationalism (Box 38, Folder 536-538)
    - Continental reform (Box 38, Folder 539)
    - Covenant theology (Box 38, Folder 540)
    - Cultivated man (Box 38, Folder 541)
    - Curio and Joris (Box 38, Folder 542)
    - Democracy (Box 38, Folder 543)
    - Early Church and Middle Ages (Box 38, Folder 544)
    - Enlightenment (Box 38, Folder 545)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -Adagia (Box 38, Folder 546)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -Apologies (Box 38, Folder 547)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -Bible (Box 38, Folder 548)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -Bibliographical (Box 38, Folder 549)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -Ciceronianus (Box 38, Folder 550)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -Colloquies (Box 39, Folder 551)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -Contemporaries (Box 39, Folder 552)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -Epistolae (Box 39, Folder 553)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -Letters (Box 39, Folder 554,555)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -New Testament editions (Box 39, Folder 556)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -No abiding place (Box 39, Folder 557)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -N.Y. Public and Morgan (Box 39, Folder 558)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -Pacis (Box 39, Folder 559)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -Primary (Box 39, Folder 560)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -Querela Pacis (Box 39, Folder 561)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -Secondary (Box 39, Folder 562-564)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -Sources (Box 39, Folder 565)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -Works (Box 39, Folder 566)
    - Desiderius Erasmus -misc. notes (Box 39, Folder 567-571)
    - Family life; Homosexuality (Box 40, Folder 572)
    - France (Box 40, Folder 573)
    - Sebastian Franck (Box 40, Folder 574)
    - German church (Box 40, Folder 575)
    - Greece (Box 40, Folder 576)